<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-23T18:15:46-04:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/</id><title type="html">TheoPanag</title><subtitle>Software Engineer - M.S. Georgia Tech</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hey there, welcome!</title><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/hello" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hey there, welcome!" /><published>2018-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/hello</id><content type="html" xml:base="/https://theopanag7.github.io/hello">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/profile_large.jpg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; alt=&quot;Profile Pic&quot; style=&quot;float: right; padding: 40px&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
My name is Theo and I am a Software Engineer specializing in Augmented Reality, Computer Vision and Graphics. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

If you are interested in my work, you can read about my projects &lt;a href=&quot;https://theopanag7.github.io/tag/work/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, watch some demos &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.com/user/TheoPanag7&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or download the source code &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/theopanag7&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to learn more about me and my journey keep reading!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

I grew up in Athens, Greece. My mother is from New York and my father from Istiaia.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

I received my Electrical &amp; Computer Engineering degree (5yr) from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ece.upatras.gr/en/&quot;&gt;University of Patras&lt;/a&gt;, in 2016. During my time in UPatras, I researched the field of Augmented Reality under the supervision of the brilliant &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.gr/citations?hl=en&amp;user=E361geAAAAAJ&amp;view_op=list_works&amp;sortby=pubdate&quot;&gt;Konstantinos Moustakas&lt;/a&gt;. Together, we worked on a project called &lt;a href=&quot;https://theopanag7.github.io/ar-3d-maps&quot;&gt;'Augmented Reality 3D Maps'&lt;/a&gt; which led to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://theopanag7.github.io/contours-paper&quot;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt; soon after graduation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

During the summers of 2015 and 2016 I interned as a Software Engineer with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mantis.group/&quot;&gt;Mantis Informatics S.A.&lt;/a&gt;, where I developed Heads Up Display (HUD) applications for warehouse environments. I worked with various devices (Vuzix M100, Moverio BT-200, etc) and attempted to reduce the time spent in the most expensive process of warehousing: Order Picking.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

After graduation, I embarked on my 9 month mandatory military service in the Greek Army (NATO forces); first as a tank commander on the border and finally as an engineer in Athens HQ.

&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/wordcloud.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Word Map&quot;&gt;

Upon completion of my service (Aug. 2017), I moved to the US to pursue my MS CS degree in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gatech.edu/&quot;&gt;Georgia Tech&lt;/a&gt;, where I specialize in Computer Graphics &amp; Vision. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

During school time, I work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cc.gatech.edu/home/thad/&quot;&gt;Dr. Thad Starner&lt;/a&gt;, inventor of Google Glass and HMD expert, as a Head Teaching Assistant for his Artificial Intelligence graduate course. As Head TA I lead a team of 15+ GTAs, managing 400+ online graduate students and 100+ on-campus. I am responsible for substitute teaching, course content, midterm and final exams etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

Under his supervision, I also research the field of Head Mounted Displays and Wearables, working on various different projects and publications (&lt;a href=&quot;https://theopanag7.github.io/hud-rfid&quot;&gt;latest paper on ISWIC '2018&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

During the summer I interned with Amway as a Software Engineer, working on mobile Augmented Reality. I worked in the R&amp;D department, developing interactive AR applications for Amway's own product lines. My &lt;a href=&quot;https://theopanag7.github.io/amway&quot;&gt;app prototypes&lt;/a&gt; were received well and were ultimately incorporated into production. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;


Let's &lt;a href=&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/theopanag1993&quot;&gt;connect&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Theo Panagiotopoulos</name></author><category term="about" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Head Teaching Assistant in Artificial Intelligence</title><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/head-ta" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Head Teaching Assistant in Artificial Intelligence" /><published>2018-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/head-ta</id><content type="html" xml:base="/https://theopanag7.github.io/head-ta">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During Fall 2018, I work as a Head Teaching Assistant for Georgia Tech's graduate-level Artificial Intelligence course (CS6601).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work closely with Dr. Thad Starner, inventor of Google Glass and Symbiotic AI pioneer, helping him prepare, run and improve the course. I lead a team of 13 Graduate Teaching Assistants and I am responsible for 590 graduate students (140 on-campus, 450 online).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started as a Graduate Teaching Assistant in Spring 2018, and became a Head TA a semester later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;formattingtext&quot;&gt;Responsiblities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creation of the Midterm and Final exam questions. The exams are around 30-40pp, are take-home, and test various different aspects of AI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development and maintenance of Python-based AI projects for the students. The projects are hosted on the cloud, are auto-graded and span various different subjects. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordination of student communications on various online platforms (Piazza, Slack, Google Hangouts etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Substitute Teaching a class of 100+ students on AI research topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating course content with recent AI research papers, articles and videos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;formattingtext&quot;&gt;Subjects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
- Game Playing&lt;br&gt;
- Search&lt;br&gt;
- Simulated Annealing&lt;br&gt;
- Constraint Satisfaction Problems&lt;br&gt;
- Probability&lt;br&gt;
- Bayes Nets&lt;br&gt;
- Machine Learning (Clustering, Decision Trees, Neural Nets, Deep Learning)&lt;br&gt;
- Pattern Recognition through Time (DTW, HMMs)&lt;br&gt;
- Logic and Planning&lt;br&gt;
- Planning under Uncertainty&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Theo Panagiotopoulos</name></author><category term="work-experience" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Augmented Reality Intern</title><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/amway" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Augmented Reality Intern" /><published>2018-05-14T05:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-14T05:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/amway</id><content type="html" xml:base="/https://theopanag7.github.io/amway">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Summer of 2018 I interned with Amway's R&amp;D, working on mobile Augmented Reality (AR) applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job was to explore Augmented Reality as a technology and find possible use cases for Amway. To that end, I designed and developed 2 AR prototypes focused on interactive packaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal was to enhance the &lt;i&gt;Amway experience&lt;/i&gt; by adding a digital extension to Amway packages. I worked on both the social/promotional aspect of Augmented Reality as well as the immersive/entertaining one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internship involved a final presentation, where I pitched my work and its importance to approximately 100 Amway employees (management, marketing, etc.). The presentation included live demos of the prototypes and an extensive Q&amp;A session. The project was received very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;formattingtext&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I developed 2 &lt;b&gt;iOS&lt;/b&gt; applications, using &lt;b&gt;Obj-C&lt;/b&gt; (not Swift, because of library limitations). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AR applications were built on the &lt;b&gt;Vuforia&lt;/b&gt; AR library, and on a combination of &lt;b&gt;OpenGL ES&lt;/b&gt; &amp; &lt;b&gt;Scenekit&lt;/b&gt; for 3D rendering. Additional tools like &lt;b&gt;Blender&lt;/b&gt; were also utilized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Theo Panagiotopoulos</name></author><category term="work-experience" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Head Mounted Displays in Warehouses</title><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/hud-rfid" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Head Mounted Displays in Warehouses" /><published>2018-05-11T01:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-11T01:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/hud-rfid</id><content type="html" xml:base="/https://theopanag7.github.io/hud-rfid">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the best part of my time here in Georgia Tech I have worked with &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=qr8Vo9IAAAAJ&amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Dr. Thad Starner&lt;/a&gt; as a researcher in Head Mounted Displays. Thad is a great mentor; he's a Georgia Tech Professor, the director of the Contextual Computing Group and the Technical Lead on Google Glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with Thad, Charu Thomas, Pramod Kotipalli and Sarthak Srinivas we've been exploring the disruptive potential of Head Mounted Displays in the Warehousing industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 &gt;Why Warehouses?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The rise of Head Mounted Displays will inevitably impact all industries that rely on human labor. More than 55% of the operational costs of a warehouse are spent in a process called 'Order Picking', where employees travel around the warehouse collecting items and fulfilling customer orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the highly specialized nature of this task, it is a task still largely done manually. The industry standard right now involves &lt;i&gt;pickers&lt;/i&gt; carrying paper lists or handheld barcode scanners, both solutions being far from ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/googleglass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Google Glass&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head Mounted Displays have the potential to revolutionize Order Picking since they allow pickers to have both hands free for the actual picking task. They can provide navigation services, highlight the items on the racks for easier picking and much more.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My contribution to the field involves two projects; one focused on RFID wearables for verification and one tackling in-doors navigation. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 &gt;Heads Up Displays with RFID verification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heads Up Displays have already been proven to increase picking speed. They still, however, face a big challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/hud-rfid-collage.jpg#full&quot; alt=&quot;hud-rfid-collage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When pickers scan item locations with a barcode scanner, the Warehouse Management System (WMS) verifies that they're picking the correct item saving them from potential errors. Heads Up Displays lack such a verification system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to give an answer to this shortcoming by utilizing wearable RFID bands. The bands would recognize passive RFID tags located near bins, and would seamlessly verify a pick, returning positive or negative results straight to the HUD (Google Glass). We developed and tested our method against current industry standards (pick-by-paper, pick-to-light, pick-by-barcode).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/hud-rfid-layout.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HUD-RFID-layout&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We conducted a 12 person user study in a model warehouse and found our method to be faster, less prone to errors and less taxing to the users than all methods currently used in the industry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work was published in the International Symbosium on Wearable Computers, ISWC '18, in Singapore, with the title- &lt;i&gt;&quot;RF-Pick: Comparing Order Picking Using a HUD with Wearable RFID Verification to Traditional Pick Methods&quot;&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 &gt;In-doors Navigation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reducing picking time and errors only solves part of the problem. 50% of the time and thus the cost of Order Picking is spent in-between picks, when a picker is walking from one location to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to reduce the travelling time by means of optimization and navigation. Warehouses are complicated structures and can become very crowded and very hectic. A navigation system, like an in-doors &lt;i&gt;Maps&lt;/i&gt; application, can help pickers traverse the Warehouse more quickly and more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal was not to design an in-doors Real Time Location System (RTLS) since such systems already exist. Instead, we focused on the client application that would run on a Heads Up Display. Ultimately we wanted to investigate whether such a Navigation system could reduce travelling time and by what amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/navigation-library.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Navigation Project in library&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tested our method in Georgia Tech's library. We gave subjects a list of books either in a paper form or directly to the HUD, and they would have to pick them and fulfill the order. Our goal was to determine whether HUD with Navigation could actually reduce the time wasted in between picks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study is still on-going.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Theo Panagiotopoulos</name></author><category term="research" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html">For the best part of my time here in Georgia Tech I have worked with Dr. Thad Starner as a researcher in Head Mounted Displays. Thad is a great mentor; he's a Georgia Tech Professor, the director of the Contextual Computing Group and the Technical Lead on Google Glass.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lattice Mesh Generation</title><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/3d-lattice" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lattice Mesh Generation" /><published>2017-12-06T05:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-06T05:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/3d-lattice</id><content type="html" xml:base="/https://theopanag7.github.io/3d-lattice">&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project was to generate a custom 3D lattice support structure in between two arbitrary surfaces. These single-mesh lattice structures have a variety of uses in the medical field. They can be 3D printed and inserted into the human body to support a vain or a damaged organ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jDTrdmlcgTU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's the process we followed given two arbitrary planar point clouds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We first triangulate (Delaunay) the two point clouds and generate two parallel planar surfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We then implement Delaunay Tetrahedralization to fill the space in between the two planes with tetrahedra primitives.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We use the edges of the tetrahedra as support beams for our lattice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, we use the ball-pivoting algorithm to generate a single 3D mesh from all the primitives. This step is crucial since it allows 3D printing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project completed by me and Sandeep Bangalore at Georgia Tech, Atlanta.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Theo Panagiotopoulos</name></author><category term="projects" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html">The goal of this project was to generate a custom 3D lattice support structure in between two arbitrary surfaces. These single-mesh lattice structures have a variety of uses in the medical field. They can be 3D printed and inserted into the human body to support a vain or a damaged organ.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hackathon 1st place</title><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/hack-gt" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hackathon 1st place" /><published>2017-10-13T06:18:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-13T06:18:00-04:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/hack-gt</id><content type="html" xml:base="/https://theopanag7.github.io/hack-gt">&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/theopanag7/card-cache&quot;&gt;Card-Cache application&lt;/a&gt; won the 1st prize in the Career App challenge in the Hack GT 2017 Hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Card-Cache is a mobile app which can detect business cards, parse them, translate them and save them in your e-wallet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team consisted of 4 people. My responsibilities were to handle the Computer Vision aspects of the app (detection, parsing and translation).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Theo Panagiotopoulos</name></author><category term="achievements" /><summary type="html">Our Card-Cache application won the 1st prize in the Career App challenge in the Hack GT 2017 Hackathon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Georgia Tech</title><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/georgia-tech" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Georgia Tech" /><published>2017-08-14T06:18:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-14T06:18:00-04:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/georgia-tech</id><content type="html" xml:base="/https://theopanag7.github.io/georgia-tech">&lt;p&gt;I’m currently pursuing a Master’s Degree in Computer Science. I will be graduating on May 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m specializing in Computer Graphics and Vision and I am currently working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=qr8Vo9IAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Dr. Thad Starner&lt;/a&gt; both in &lt;a href=&quot;/hud-rfid&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt; and as a &lt;a href=&quot;/head-ta&quot;&gt;Head TA&lt;/a&gt; in the Artificial Intelligence course.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Theo Panagiotopoulos</name></author><category term="education" /><summary type="html">I’m currently pursuing a Master’s Degree in Computer Science. I will be graduating on May 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Arrival in the USA</title><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/arrival-USA" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arrival in the USA" /><published>2017-08-14T03:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-14T03:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/arrival-USA</id><content type="html" xml:base="/https://theopanag7.github.io/arrival-USA">&lt;p&gt;On August 14th, I arrived to the United States, starting my MS degree in Computer Science at Georgia Tech.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Theo Panagiotopoulos</name></author><category term="life-events" /><summary type="html">On August 14th, I arrived to the United States, starting my MS degree in Computer Science at Georgia Tech.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mandatory Military Service</title><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/military-service" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mandatory Military Service" /><published>2016-11-07T05:18:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-07T05:18:00-05:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/military-service</id><content type="html" xml:base="/https://theopanag7.github.io/military-service">&lt;p&gt;I have completed my mandatory military service (9 months) in the Greek Army.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I served in Protokklisi, a small village on the Greco-Turkish border, as a Tank Commander for 6 months. 
For my final 3 months, I returned to Athens to serve in the Engineer Corps, Army HQ.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Theo Panagiotopoulos</name></author><category term="life-events" /><summary type="html">I have completed my mandatory military service (9 months) in the Greek Army.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">University of Patras</title><link href="/https://theopanag7.github.io/upatras" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="University of Patras" /><published>2016-07-21T06:18:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-07-21T06:18:00-04:00</updated><id>/https://theopanag7.github.io/upatras</id><content type="html" xml:base="/https://theopanag7.github.io/upatras">&lt;p&gt;I graduated from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.upatras.gr/en&quot;&gt;University of Patras&lt;/a&gt; in 2016, with a B.E. in Electrical &amp;amp; Computer Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Engineering Degree in Greece is a 5 year program with a 2 year specialization. My specialization was in Electronics &amp;amp; Computers and my &lt;a href=&quot;/ar-3d-maps&quot;&gt;Thesis was in Augmented Reality&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my 4th and 5th year, I worked in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vvr.ece.upatras.gr/index.php/en/&quot;&gt;VVR lab&lt;/a&gt; under the supervision of &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.gr/citations?hl=en&amp;amp;user=E361geAAAAAJ&amp;amp;view_op=list_works&amp;amp;sortby=pubdate&quot;&gt;Konstantinos Moustakas&lt;/a&gt; working in Computer Vision and Computer Graphics projects. You can find samples of my work &lt;a href=&quot;/contours-pathfinding&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/tetris-3d&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I graduated in the top 12% of my class with a 7.82/10 grade. I was also in the 3% that managed to finish the degree in the 5 year time-frame.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Theo Panagiotopoulos</name></author><category term="education" /><summary type="html">I graduated from the University of Patras in 2016, with a B.E. in Electrical &amp;amp; Computer Engineering.</summary></entry></feed>